Engineering]

Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Kumar Bhashkar Alok (1) Featured

Senior Consultant seeking roles in Database Development, Data
Warehousing, Database Architecture, Data Modeling, Data Extraction, Performance
Tuning, ETL Development, PL/SQL, SQL, Oracle, SQL Developer, Oracle
Apex, HTML, JavaScript, JDA Demand



Current Designation: Senior Consultant -Database

Current Company: Cognizant

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore
Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Tech Lead, Database Development, Data Warehousing, Data Architecture, Data Modeling, Data Extraction, Business Intelligence, Performance Tuning, ETL Development, PL/SQL, SQL, Oracle, SQL

Developer, Apex, HTML, Java Script, JDA Demand

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

8 years of IT experience in software application development and support using Oracle technologies like PL/SQL, SQL. Excellent working experience in PL/SQL

Excellent working experience in SQL

IT Experience in support of JDA SCPO suite of applications i.e. JDA Demand, JDA Fulfillment

Excellent exposure in Performance Tuning for Oracle RDBMS using Explain Plan, GTT, Indexes, HINTS and performance reports(ADDM, AWR)

Worked on Oracle 10g, Oracle 11g, Oracle 12c databases

Excellent working experience in Anonymous blocks, Oracle Packages, Triggers, Functions, Stored Procedures, Objects, Types and other DB objects

Hands on Experience in views and M views

Knowledge in UTL_FILE Package and Data Loading using SQL*Loader, External table

Hands on experience of application development on Oracle Apex version 4.2, 5.1

Work Experience

Cognizant as Senior Consultant -Database May 2019 to Till Date

PLSQL Developer

Oracle India as Programmer Analyst

Jul 2016 to May 2019

R Systems International Ltd. as Software Developer

Jun 2014 to Jul 2016

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Annamalai University in 2011

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JDA Demand			
PL/SQL, SQL			
Unix			
Windows, Ubuntu 12.04			
Oracle 10g/11g/12c			
SQL DEVELOPER			
MS OFFICE			
Winscp, Super putty			
CA7			
APEX			
HTML, JavaScript			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Walmart (Global Replenishment System)

Client: Walmart (USA)

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: SQL, PL/SQL, Shell Scripting

Project Details: The Global Replenishment System (GRS) project was initiated by Walmart to design, develop and deploy a common global cross platform for replenishment planning and purchase order execution. The project mainly deals with JDA Demand, Fulfillment, Order Optimizer and Promotion modules by Walmart and its subsidiaries globally.

We are mainly dealing entire transaction directly with client. JDA planning engine fulfils the requirements of goods to Walmart stores for specified planning duration from Regional Distribution Center to Distribution centers and Stores.

Project Title: EVP Setup Audit Tool

Client: Internal Project

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2018 - Mar 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: PLSQL Developer cum Apex developer

Project Details: EVP Setup Audit is the process to check the EVP Resources set up between Account Receivable (AR) tool data & Fusion/Territory tool setup to ensure a synchrony between these two systems. With the help of these checks, BPS & Field finance Teams can work on and fix the EVP Resources which are not mapped with Fusion/Territory tool setup so that the Automatic Revenue allocation logic will work appropriately and Revenue flows to the correct EVP Resources. This audit process we were doing monthly once manually.

Now we have created Apex tool dashboard for this EVP Setup Audit, where data refreshes daily at 8PM PST. Apex tool pulls the Active sales reps data from GCW ODSAP tool and Territory data from Fusion CRM Database.

Project Title: Rcode Selection Tool Client: Oracle Internal Project Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2016 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle 12C

Project Details: Rcode selection tool is an Apex application which takes the R-code Organization metadata from the existing R-code utility and overlays a user interface which allows users to select what members are needed for forecasting, budgeting, etc. The system then performs some pre-set logic and output the metadata into a CSV file in parent/child format (for load into existing and future GBF Hyperion Development Hyperion Planning/Essbase applications).

The key functionality/process flow is as follows:

User (with write access) selects desired selection scenario

System provides adjusted R-code hierarchy (one-to-one and orphaned members removed)

User navigates up/down hierarchy and selects desired members

User is able to copy selections from another scenario, clear existing selections, or undo last action System automatically adds siblings, ancestors, and ancestors of siblings based on user activity

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time